realtimepolitics.com 2019-10-21

# Privacy Policy – Realtime Politics

Realtime Politics (“ **Realtime Politics** “) operates https://realtimepolitics.com and may operate other websites. It is Realtime Politics‘s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Realtime Politics collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Realtime Politics‘s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Realtime Politics‘s visitors use its website. From time to time, Realtime Politics may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Realtime Politics also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on https://realtimepolitics.com blogs/sites. Realtime Politics only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog/site where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Realtime Politics‘s websites choose to interact with Realtime Politics in ways that require Realtime Politics to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Realtime Politics gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up at Realtime Politics to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Realtime Politics are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Realtime Politics collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Realtime Politics. Realtime Politics does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Realtime Politics may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Realtime Politics may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Realtime Politics does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Realtime Politics discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Realtime Politics‘s behalf or to provide services available at Realtime Politics‘s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Realtime Politics‘s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Realtime Politics will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Realtime Politics discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Realtime Politics believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Realtime Politics, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Realtime Politics website and have supplied your email address, Realtime Politics may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Realtime Politics and our products. If you send us a request (for example via email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Realtime Politics takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Realtime Politics uses cookies to help Realtime Politics identify and track visitors, their usage of Realtime Politics website, and their website access preferences. Realtime Politics visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Realtime Politics‘s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Realtime Politics‘s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**

If Realtime Politics, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Realtime Politics goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Realtime Politics may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Realtime Politics and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Brainsation participates in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. For more information please visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website or use our apps. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies for interest based advertising, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

How to opt out  
<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/>

**Log Data**

We may also collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this type of information in order to increase our Service’s functionality. These third party service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information.

**Communications**

We may use your Personal Information to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

**Compliance With Laws**

We will disclose your Personal Information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement or to protect the security or integrity of our Service.

**Security**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, and we strive to implement and maintain reasonable, commercially acceptable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information we store, in order to protect it from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure.

However, please be aware that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and we are unable to guarantee the absolute security of the Personal Information we have collected from you.

**International Transfer**

Your information, including Personal Information, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the information, including Personal Information, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links To Other Sites**

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

**Children’s Privacy**

Only persons age 18 or older have permission to access our Service. Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 (“Children”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you learn that your Children have provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Realtime Politics may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Realtime Politics‘s sole discretion. Realtime Politics encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a Realtime Politics account, you might also receive an alert informing you of these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
